Jason Goodell

860-888-6797 jasongoodell@me.com 4917 Dan David Dr Raleigh NC, 27606, USA

Profile

A Python developer with the language and platform experience dating back more than 10 years. Has experience with three major Python web development frameworks; Django, Flask, and Pyramid, including the development of web APIs. Experience with Python package development for code reuse across varying application contexts. Python scripting experience for database record CrUD detection, and extraction scripting for data warehouse ETL processes.

Experience

PRINCIPLE ENGINEER, COMCAST COMPANY TPX CCS ACS; ARLINGTON, VA - 2020-PRESENT

Principle engineer on the data flow team responsible for the APIs used to transfer, manage, and store threat detection signature data on the Advanced Threat Detection (ATD) platform. Implemented the transition from Redis key value storage of threat signatures to PostGres SQL storage, implemented Celery messaging with Redis broker and PostGres backend, for the concurrent processing of third party threat detection data in ATD. Designed and implemented a python package for bulk data transfer of large files over HTTP using the RANGE HTTP header to break up the file data into byte ranges, reassembling the complete file on the receiving end of the transfer. The python bulk data transfer package supports both upload (POST and PUT) and download (GET) of large files over HTTP. Also responsible for providing elevated support for platform testers and customer support engineers.

- Python 3.X w/ pyenv
- Flask for service and web app development.
- Swagger/Open API API definition and documentation for Flask
- Docker with Docker Compose
- Celery and Redis
- tox for unit testing and linting of code base
- BitBucket Git Repository for
- PostGres
- Agile Scrum with JIRA.

PYTHON DEVELOPER, GLOBAL KNOWLEDGE; CARY, NC - 2017-2020

Server side developer on the self-paced learning offering based on the Open edX platform. Created and supported client facing features like message to email relays for technical support and learning support using, added additional API endpoints for user course certificates retrieval, and developed a custom Django authentication backend for single sign on integration with Global Knowledge's Identity Server. Designed and developed a messaging relay service to asynchronously manage incoming registrations to the self-paced learning platform. Lead developer for integrating virtual instructor lead event schedule with our new web meeting partner Zoom. Built the automated service that pushes event scheduling to Zoom through Zoom's web API for meeting management. Developed and built a Flask based web app for our internal help desk. The web app allows our help desk to edit Zoom meetings for events within an hour of the meetings start, without having to use the Zoom Admin, and keeps our operational data about Zoom meetings in synch with meetings scheduled in Zoom.

- Python 2.7 w/ virtualenv wrapper
- Django 1.8 (for custom EdX app development)
- Flask for service and web app development
- Open EdX (Django 1.8 based application)
- RabbitMQ with Celery and Redis
- MySQL 5
- Agile Scrum.

SERVER-SIDE PYTHON DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR), SENSUS; DURHAM, NC - 2016-2016

Django web development consultant on a small team developing web applications. The web application aids component engineers in managing demand planning for Sensus' smart meter manufacturing.

- Python 2.7 w/ virtualenv wrapper
- Django 1.8
- PostGres 9.5
- Ubuntu 16.04 on Vagrant w/ Docker for development environments
- Bootstrap and AngularJS for prototyping interfaces
- Demand based free-form project planning.

SERVER-SIDE PYTHON DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR), CISCO; MORRISVILLE, NC - 2015-2016

Server side web developer for CIS (Cloud Information Security) devision. On a small team developing an integrated security platform prototype that ties Qualys and serverspec into a single interface for threat assessment.

- Python 2.6 w/ virtualenv wrapper
- Django 1.9
- PostGres 9.4
- Ubuntu 14.04 on Vagrant w/ Docker for development environments
- Bootstrap and AngularJS for prototyping interfaces
- Agile-ish, 3 week sprints with stories, weekly checkins and back-log.

SERVER-SIDE PYTHON DEVELOPER (REMOTE CONTRACTOR), IBM SECURITY SERVICES; BOULDER, CO – 2014-2015

Server side developer for the IBM's SecMart team. The team is responsible for the extraction, transformation and loading (ETL) of security scan data into IBM's security data warehouse.

- Python 2.7
- MySQL 5
- CentOS 5
- Demand based free-form project planning with daily checkins.

SERVER-SIDE PYTHON DEVELOPER (REMOTE CONTRACTOR), HARRISON COLLEGE; INDIANAPOLIS, IN – 2014-2014

Server side developer for the company's education hub product KnowU, which ties together electronic course management and student information systems with social networking platforms.

- Python 2.7 w/ virtualenv
- Django 1.7
- Ubuntu 14.04 on Vagrant for development environments
- PostGres 9.2
- MongoDB evaluated for messaging backend with Celery & RabbitMQ
- Agile, 2-week sprints, stories with backlog, planning poker, and burn-down.

PRIMARY PYTHON DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR), DUKE CLINICAL RESEARCH INSTITUTE; DURHAM, NC –

A Web application developer updating an internal questionnaire framework created for physicians to record patient surveys.

- Python 2.6
- Pyramid 1.5 w/ SQLAlchemy
- Ubuntu 12 on Vagrant
- PostGres 9.2
- Demand based project planning with monthly checkins.

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, EPOCRATES AN ATHENAHEALTH COMPANY; DURHAM, NC – 2011-2014

A Python/XSLT/iOS developer charged with the marshaling and development of data used to drive the Epocrates line of physician reference applications. Designed an implemented a web application CMS for cancer treatment decision graphs.

- Python 2.6 w/ virtualenv
- Pyramid 1.2 w/ SQLAlchemy
- MacOS X
- Ubuntu 12 for production
- MySQL 5
- JQuery
- Agile, 4-week sprints, stories with backlog, planning poker, and burn-down.

Education

University of Connecticut; Storrs, CT – B.S. Physics Manchester Community College; Manchester, CT – A.S. General Studies